A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Program Related Investments, Administrative Files FA686
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Program Related Investments, Administrative Files
1971-1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA686
1.64 Cubic Feet
Separated Materials
Appendix A: Reports – Unpublished reports written by Ford Foundation staff and consultants were removed from their original folders, scanned and transferred to the Archives' collection of staff and consultant reports. See Appendix A for a list of these reports and their specific assigned number. The reports are listed in alphabetical order by author. The assigned number may be used to access reports in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1986-1987
Series II. Consultant Files, 1971-1991
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence and consultant files.
Conditions Governing Access
Records more than 10 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1986-1987; I
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 January 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 January 16-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 February 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 February 16-28 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 March 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 March 16-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 April 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 April 16-30 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 May 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 May 16-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 June 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 June 16-30 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 July 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 July 16-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 August 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 August 15-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 September 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 September 15-30 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 October 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 October 15-31 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 November 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 November 15-30 (Box 1)
  - 1986 PRI Chron File, 1986 December 1-31 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 January 1-15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 January 15-February 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 February 15-March 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 March 15-April 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 April 15-May 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 May 16-June 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 June 16-July 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 July 15-August 13 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 August 15-September 15 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 September 15-October 17 (Box 1)
  - 1987 PRI Chron File, 1987 October 15-December 15 (Box 1)
- Consultant Files, 1971-1991; II
  - Alexander and Associates, Inc. (Alan Patricoff) -- "Corporate Social Responsibility", 1982 May (Box 2)
  - Arrick, Ellen -- "Financing Low-Income Housing with Private Capital: The Experience of the Bank Lending Consortia" by Ellen Arrick, 1991 January (Box 2)
  - Banks, Pearl Howell -- "Emergency Funds: A Survey of Nonprofit Assistance Funds" by Pearl Howell Banks, 1989 June (Box 2)
  - Boss, Richard -- "Final Report on RLG" by Richard Boss, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Brody and Weiser -- "Equity Grant Review" Prepared for Ellen Arrick, 1988 August (Box 2)
  - DeGiovanni, Frank F. -- "Assessment of the Ford Foundation PRI Loan to the National Trust for Historic Preservation's Inner City Ventures Fund" by Frank F. DeGiovanni, 1985 August (Box 2)
  - DeGiovanni, Frank F. -- "Evaluation of the Bay Area Residential Investment and Development Group (BRIDGE)" by Frank F. DeGiovanni, 1987 October (Box 2)
  - Doran, John -- Connecticut Housing Investment Fund (CHIF), 1971 (Box 2)
  - Green, W. James -- "An Applied Analytical Methodology for the Conduct of Demand and Market Analyses in Select Industrial Sectors" by W. James Green, 1981 September (Box 2)
  - Gruenberg, Paul -- Correspondence Re: Consultancy, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - Lanier, Catherine Bragg -- "The Fund for Private Assistance in International Development (PAID): An Assessment of Financial Condition and Long-term Business Strategy" by Catherine Bragg Lanier and James Braidy Steinberg, 1989 July 24 (Box 2)
  - Leibowitz, Arnold H. -- "Analysis of the Operations of the Neighborhood Housing Services,Inc." by Arnold H. Leibowitz, 1973 June 7 (Box 2)
  - Trinkaus, John W. -- Consultancy Reports -- Support Services Alliance Inc., Anthology Film Archives, Black Gentlemen Communications Company, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Walker A. Williams and Company -- Report Re: Non-Profit Public Interest Hotel Facility (Washington, DC), 1977-1978 (Box 2)